Aaliyah asked Noah to identify which new ideas developed by his team are the most effective for MODA to invest in as a part of this transformation.
So Noah reaches out to Maryam, who can help him gather and analyse information from across the Digital team on their top three ideas.
Maryam has spent the last week talking to different members of Noah’s team to gather the reasons why these ideas are the best to pursue.
There was a ton of information to work with, but she now feels confident to share her findings with Noah.
“And the second idea is a very good idea from Penelope, which proposes in-store self-serve tablets.
I can walk you through the report on the estimated costs and benefits.” “Okay, but first…”
“That reminds me that Harry also shared how his idea builds on Penelope’s idea, and…”
“You want this. It shows how everything can integrate with a new point-of-sale system.”
“Maryam…” “And?”
“One last thing on the third idea — super important given the recent advances in technology.
We can negotiate an extremely favourable price with our vendor and save money in the long term. Oh, before I forget…” “Maryam.”
“Maryam!” “I’m out.”
“I’m sorry to cut you off. This is all really interesting indeed.
But have we answered yet why these are the best ideas to pursue?”
“Oh. I wanted to share all of the findings from the team first. They did so much work.”
“It’s really great work. You definitely have all the right pieces.
You just need to find a way to communicate it in a clearer way.
How about we structure the information you have received so far?” “Okay.” “In our meeting with Aaliyah,
we want to lead with the answer — the governing thought — and then provide the reasoning and facts to support it.
Here’s what I had in mind. Let’s use this as a starting point.”
“Right.” “Now, this key message will raise a new question in the reader’s mind, such as “why?” or “how?”.
To answer that question, we need to go down to the next level — or key line — to answer why these three ideas are the best to invest in.
That will prompt another question, which we can answer with the supporting facts.
Let’s group the information you’ve collected and see what themes emerge.
Then we can figure out why each group of facts really matters — what people refer to as the “so what”.” “Got it.”